usb.org 2019-07-11

# Privacy Statement | USB-IF

### Privacy Statement for USB Implementers Forum, Inc.   
(www.usb.org)

USB Implementers Forum, Inc. (USB-IF) has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for personal data collected by this website. 

#### IP Address 

We use the IP addresses of visitors to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our Web site, and to infer general geographic information of our visitors to better improve access to the website. 

#### Registration Forms 

Our site's registration forms may require you to give us contact information (like name and email address), financial information (like credit card numbers), and demographic information (like zip code or hotel preferences). We use this information to process orders on your behalf, to contact you when necessary to resolve issues about your order or registration, and to facilitate accommodations on your behalf.

We also use your contact information from the registration form to send you information about USB-IF. Users consent to this by using clicking on the checkbox in the registration form. You may opt-out of these communications at any time; see the choice/opt out section below.

#### Order Forms 

Our site uses order forms for customers to request information about us, our products, and our services. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address), financial information (like their credit card numbers), and demographic information (like their zip code). We use the information you provide to process your order, including payment, shipment, and to contact you if there is a problem with your order or if we require more information. 

We also use your contact information from the registration form to send you information about our organization. Users consent to this by using clicking on the checkbox in the registration form. You may opt-out of these communications at any time; see the choice/opt out section below.

In order to protect your legal interests and the interests of other members, we may require you to sign a license agreement in connection with your order.

#### Personal Data of USB-IF Members

All membership information is used in accordance with the membership agreement and bylaws. We collect the contact and personal information of our members in order to provide membership benefits, such as participation in forums, communications about USB-IF events, and to communicate information to members regarding membership status. We also collect payment information from members to bill them for products and services ordered.

A member's name and email address is also available to all other members in a contact list in a password-protected area. Members control whether or not their name is displayed on this contact list by accessing the options in the member section of the website.

#### Length of Retention

USB-IF may retain personal information for as long as you maintain your membership (or as long as your employer or company maintains membership), as long as necessary to administer applicable programs or to protect contractual or intellectual-property rights, as long as required by law, or as long as you consent to receive communications from us.  For personal information gathered in connection with attendance at general meetings or conferences that is not covered above, in the immediately preceding sentence, USB-IF may retain such information for up to 5 years.

#### Links 

This site contains links to other sites. USB-IF is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

#### Disclosures to Third Parties

Our site is developed, hosted and maintained by a third party who has access to all information on this site. This "Powered by" partner is responsible for maintaining the privacy described in this statement. The third party retains no rights or privileges associated with the information (i.e. cannot distribute, sell, exchange the information collected).

In addition, USB-IF uses contractors to provide support staff and technology services to USB-IF that may have access to your personal information for the purposes of processing outlined in this statement. Those third parties are under contractual obligations to keep your information confidential and to only process the data at USB-IF's direction.

#### Cookies 

We use cookies on our site to recognize your browser to ease access to our member areas. We also evaluate the information obtained from your browsing habits of this website to understand how people use our website so we can make it more intuitive.  

#### Forums 

This site makes forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. The web site may have both "members only" (password-protected) forums and "non-members" forums. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas may become public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

#### Security 

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. The physical devices running this site are located in a secure facility. A high-strength firewall protects our database from outsiders. Access to many areas of our site is password protected. We use Secure Socket Layers (SSL) to encrypt sensitive data you send us. All credit card transactions are handled by a reputable third party banking and processing institution. They receive the information needed to verify and authorize a customer's credit card and process the order.

#### Choice/Opt-Out 

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor.

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database so as to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

You can send email to admin@usb.org  
You can send mail to the following postal address:  
3855 SW 153rd Drive, Beaverton, OR  97003, USA  
You can call the following number: +1 (503) 619-0426

Members who are the individuals designated by their company as being in charge of the member company's product may not opt out of product-related mailings, as receiving this information is an integral part of membership; such individuals should contact their member companies if they do not wish to serve in this role.

#### Correct/Update 

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

You may send email to admin@usb.org  
You may send mail to the following postal address:   
3855 SW 153rd Drive, Beaverton, OR  97003, USA  
Visit www.usb.org/members/  
You may call +1 (503) 619-0426

#### Notification of Changes 

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our web site so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

#### Rights for European Union Residents

If you reside in the European Union, you have certain rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation in regards to your personal information. These rights include a right to access and receive a copy of the personal information that we have about you, the right to correct any inaccuracies in our records, to restrict our use of your personal data, and, in some circumstances, to have us delete or remove your personal information from our records. If you wish to exercise these rights, please email us at admin@usb.org.

In the event that you request that we delete your personal information, we will remove from our records any personal information that is not necessary to (1) ensure that we do not contact you in the future and (2) protect the legal rights of USB-IF and its members, such as to ensure the protection of proprietary information of our members. In addition, while we will make every effort to remove your data from our system, we do not have control over personal data that you publish to other members, including messages placed on forums or messages sent to mailing lists.

#### Contacting the Web Site 

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact USB Implementers Forum, Inc. or email privacy@usb.org.
